newstime.co.za 2011-06-08

# Please read the Privacy Policy and our notices regarding Terms and Conditions and Forums. By continuing to use NewsTime, you agree to abide by the terms of these documents.

Please read the Privacy Policy and our notices regarding Terms and Conditions and Forums.
By continuing to use NewsTime, you agree to abide by the terms of these documents.
1. INTRODUCTION
This privacy policy ("this Privacy Policy") must be read together with the Terms and
Conditions. Unless defined elsewhere, terms in this Privacy Policy shall bear the meaning
ascribed to them in the Terms and Conditions.
    1.1. The Owner is committed to bringing You information tailored to Your individual
         needs and recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of personally
         identifiable information collected about our users.
    1.2. In adopting this Privacy Policy, the Owner wishes to balance its legitimate business
         interests when collecting and using your personal information and Your reasonable
         expectation of privacy. In this respect, the Owner will take reasonable steps to
         prevent unauthorised access to, or disclosure of your personal information.
         However, the Owner does not guarantee that Your personal information shall be
         100% secure.
    1.3. By continuing to use this Web Site, You agree to the terms and conditions of this
         Privacy Policy. If You do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not continue to
         Use The Web Site.
    1.4. You agree that the Owner may collect, collate, process and/or store Your personal
         information (as this phrase is defined in the ECT Act) ("Collect") for, amongst other
         things, the purposes of (i) providing You with access to the Web Site and the Web
         Site Content, (ii) bringing You information tailored to Your needs, and (iii)
         conducting research.
    1.5. The Owner reserves the right to vary the terms of this Privacy policy, which will be
         made available on the Web Site. It is your responsibility to familiarise Yourself with
         the most recent version of this Privacy Policy.
2.   WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION IS COLLECTED?
     2.2. The Owner may Collect personal information that may include (with limitation),
          Your name and e-mail address, information relating to Your race, gender, ethnic or
          social origin, age, well-being, disability, personal opinions, views or preferences.
3. WHEN IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED?
Personal information may be Collected in several ways.
     3.1 Some personal information may be Collected when You register for services on the
          Web Site, during the carrying out of demographic research, or when promotions,
          competitions or surveys are held.
     3.2 You acknowledge that promotions and competitions on the Web Site may be
          sponsored by third parties, or may be co-sponsored by the Owner together with
          third parties. You agree that some or all Your personal information may be shared
          with such third party.

     3.3 You also acknowledge that advertisers or other web sites that have links on the
         Web Site may also Collect Your personal information. You agree that the
         information processing practices of those advertisers and other web sites are
         neither under the control of the Owner nor regulated by this Privacy Policy.
4. HOW YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IS USED?
The primary goal in Collecting Your personal information is to provide You with a better
online experience, which may include, interactive communications, online shopping and
other services.
Your personal information may be used to:
     4.1 deliver to You more relevant and targeted content and advertisements, such as
         banner advertisements;
     4.2 conduct research related to demographics, interests and on line habits;
     4.3 compile profiles for statistical purposes. You agree that the Owner may trade with
         those profiles and statistical data. While the Owner will attempt to ensure that the
         profiles or statistical data cannot be linked to You, the Owner does not guarantee
         that third parties may not be able to link such profiles and statistical data to You.
         You hereby indemnify the Owner against any loss, liability, expense, claim, penalty
         or damage suffered by You, whether direct, indirect, special or consequential,
         arising from or in relation to any third party being able to link such profiles and
         statistical data to You;
5. WITH WHOM IS YOUR INFORMATION SHARED?
     5.1 While the Owner will attempt not to disclose any of Your personal information to
         third parties, except when we have your permission or in the legitimate business
         interests of the Owner, the Owner does not guarantee that Your personal
         information will not be shared with third parties without Your permission.
     5.2 Your personal information may also be shared under the following circumstances:
         5.2.1    where the law requires that the Owner disclose Your personal information;
         5.2.2    to monitor web traffic: web servers serving the Web Site automatically
                  collect information about pages You visit. This information is used for
                  internal review, to tailor information to individual visitors and for traffic
                  audits. This information (as well as information from third-party market
                  researchers), on an aggregated, anonymous basis, is provided to advertisers
                  advertising on the Web Site. Should You provide personal information online
                  as part of an online advertising promotion or in order to access a third party
                  service, such information may be provided directly to the advertiser or the
                  third party concerned;
         5.2.3    Promotions: many promotions offer opportunities to request additional
                  information from sponsors or third parties. When You request more
                  information about a particular promotion, Your e-mail address may be
                  shared with the sponsor of that promotion;
         5.2.4    Online shopping: if You make a purchase from an online store or merchant,
                  the information obtained during Your visit to those stores (including
                  tracking information, cookies, credit card number and contact information)
                  is provided to the merchants. This is to enable transactions to take place;
         5.2.5    Third parties: online merchants providing services in association with the
                  Owner have separate privacy and data collection practices. You agree that
                  the Owner has no responsibility or liability for third party policies. For more

                information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies,
                return to that store(s) home page and click on the appropriate link;
        5.2.6   Editorial purposes: Your personal information may be used by the Owner for
                editorial purposes. For example, this may include information You provide
                during an online survey conducted by our editors.
        5.2.7   Legal: the Owner may also disclose Your personal information in special
                cases, where the Owner has reason to believe that such disclosure is
                necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against a party who may
                be breaching the Terms and Conditions or may be causing injury to or
                interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Owner(s) rights
                or property, other users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such
                activities; and
        5.2.8   For statistics and advertisement purposes: the Owner may perform
                statistical analyses in order to measure interest in the various areas of the
                Web Site (for product development purposes) and to inform advertisers as to
                how many consumers have seen or "clicked" on their advertising banners.
                The Owner also uses demographic information to allow advertising banners
                on the Web Site to be targeted, in aggregate.
6. WHAT ARE COOKIES AND HOW ARE THEY USED?
    6.1 Cookies are pieces of information a Web Site transfers to a user(s) hard drive for
        record-keeping purposes. Cookies make surfing the web easier for You by saving
        Your preferences and, tracking Your online habits, traffic patterns, and making sure
        You do not see the same advertisement too often. The use of cookies is an industry
        standard.
    6.2 The Owner may place a "cookie" on Your browser to store and sometimes track
        information about You.
    6.3 While most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, You can reset Your
        browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. Please, note
        that some parts of the Web Site will not function properly if You refuse cookies. For
        example, without cookies, You will not be able to set personalized TV Guide
        preferences. You may occasionally get cookies from third party advertisers. The
        Owner does not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-
        party advertisers is an industry standard.
7. USE OF IP ADDRESS
    7.1 An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer whenever it
        is connected to the Internet. The Owner also logs IP addresses, or the location of
        computers on the Internet. The Owner collects IP addresses for the purposes of
        system administration, to report aggregate information to our advertisers, and to
        audit the use of the Web Site. The Owner does not ordinarily link IP addresses to
        personal information, which means that Your session may remain anonymous.
        However, the Owner cannot guarantee that this will always be the case. For
        example, it may be necessary to identify a particular user when it is necessary to
        enforce compliance with the Terms and Conditions or to protect our service Web
        Site, customers or other interests.
8. LINKS TO OTHER SITES
    8.1 When You are on the Web Site, You could be directed to other sites that are beyond
        the Owner(s) control. These other web sites may send their own cookies to You,
        collect data or solicit personal information. The Owner does not control the privacy
        policies of any advertisers, sponsors or other third party web sites.

9. SECURITY
    9.1 The importance of security for all personal information associated with You is of
        the utmost concern to us. While the Owner exercises great care in providing secure
        transmission of Your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet
        can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. The Owner cannot guarantee the security of
        any information you transmit to, or from the Owner(s) Web Site.
10. E-MAIL
    10.1 The Owner may periodically send e-mails to You about services, products or
          promotions offered by the Owner and its advertisers to the e-mail address
          provided by You.
11. POLICIES FOR INDIVIDUALS UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE
    11.1 NewsTime encourages parents, teachers and guardians to spend time online with
          their children and to participate in the activities offered on the Web Site. No
          information (including personal information) should be submitted to or posted on
          the Web Site by any person under 13 years of age without the consent of their
          parent, teacher or guardian.
